# Ali Raza

Lahore, 54590 Punjab, Pakistan +92 305 7381431 Github: alirazamumtaz LinkedIn: alirazamumtaz Webiste: alirazamumtaz.me Email: elirazamumtaz@gmail.com

#### Research Interests

My research interests lie in the intersection of computer security and low-level systems. I am interested in the security vulnerabilities posed by systems and language formal specifications, and how they can be exploited. For now, I am working on my FYP thesis that is about reproducing CVE-2019-2215 which is the Use After Free vulnerability in Android Kernel's Binder IPC subsystem.

#### Education

### **PUCIT** - University of the Punjab

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

- Expected graduation: July 2023
- GPA: 3.65/4.0

# Punjab Group of Colleges, Okara Campus

Intermediate of Computer Science with Physics

• Graduated with 3rd position in BISE Sahiwal.

September, 2019 – Present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

2017 - 2019

Okara, Punjab, Pakistan

# Research Experience

## Vulnerability Research and Exploit Development for Android Kernel

July, 2022 – Present

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Supervisor: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- Formulated the idea and initiated the research project
- Worked on problems related to memory errors in binaries
- Working on analysing Linux kernel

#### Professional Experience

#### Teaching Assistant (Operating Systems)

October, 2022 - Present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Designed material and coursework for the newly introduced lab component of the subject
- Designed exam papers for the lab
- Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

## **Programming Tutor**

April, 2022 – Present

Fiverr.com

Freelance on Fiverr

- Teaching low level programming concepts in C
- Teaching object oriented programming in C++

Programming Languages: C, Python, Java, C#, x86-64 Assembly

Security: Binary Exploitation, Reverse Engineering

Tools: IDA, GDB, GNU/Make

OS: GNU/Linux, MacOS, Windows + WSL